MILAN KACAR

Software & Survey Engineer

% https://milankacar.github.io/CV/ nilan-kacar © @milan_kacar

Scala



ABOUT ME

I am a Software Engineer & Survey Engineer with 3.5 years of professional experience. I graduated Geodesy at Graz University of Technology in Austria, where I worked as a project and teaching assistant. Currently I am working for niceshops GmbH as a Data Scientist and Data Engineer. I am also enrolled in two Master's degree programs: Geodesy & Computer Science at the same university. I grew up in Mrkonjic Grad (Republic of Srpska, BA) where I finished my high school.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of birth

O1.09.1995

Birthplace

Citizenship

Marital status

✓ Sex

Date of birth

O1.09.1995

Banja Luka, BA

Austrian

Single

Male

EDUCATION

GYMNASIUM

BSc Geomatics Engineering University of Technology, TU Graz

Master's Degree Programme - Geodesy University of Technology, TU Graz

Master's Degree Programme - Computer Science University of Technology, TU Graz

UNIVERSITY & PERSONAL PROJECTS

- SCIENTIFIC PAPER MINER Based on the publishing institutions we define our market competitors and geocode their locations. [Python/WebScraper]
- POLLEN TREE DETECTOR (FROM SATELLITE IMAGES) This project presents an automated tree detecting and identification method based on image processing of satellite imagery. [Python/keras/pytorch]
- STOCK PRICES PREDICTOR Project uses AI (Artificial intelligence) and ML (Machine learning) as a hybrid approach to detect prices fluctuation (SP 500, Dow Jones, DAX etc.) [Python/keras/pytorch]
- RUSHB APP New method to summon a waiter and order food in bars and restaurants. As a test page you can look at http://www.dolcevita.rushb.app/client.php. [JavaScript/PHP/Java]
- DIFFERENT SIGNAL PROCESSING PROJECTS Mostly projects on GNSS signals. [C++]
- GRAVITY ANOMALY MAPS GRACE misson. [Python/MATLAB]
- KALMAN FILTER ADVANCED KALMAN FILTER PARTICLE FILTER as a part of indoor navigation. [C++]
- DIFFERENT ARDUINO PROJECTS Mostly projects from youtube tutorials and combination of different projects. [C/Java/C++]

		TEC	HN	ICAL	STI	REN	GTH
--	--	-----	----	------	-----	-----	-----

Python	••••
Google Cloud	••••
C/C++	••••
GIS	••••
PostgreSQL	••••
Navigation	•••••
Cloud computing	•••••
GNSS	••••
Signal Processing	•••••
Java	••••
Data Structures & Algorithms	••••
MySQL	••••
Docker	••••
Java Script	••••
РНР	••••
Linux	••••
R	••••
Apache Spark	••••

DISSERTATION WORK

BSc Thesis

Database for cycling routes

- Entity Relationship Diagram.
- Building the Database.
- Conversion from analog to digital maps.

MSc Thesis

PV (Photovoltaic) panels detection from satellite images

- Project uses AI (Artificial intelligence) and ML (Machine learning) as a hybrid approach to detect panels.
- Building an independent model to work on different datasets.
- Cloud computing
- YOLOv5

WORK EXPERIENCE

Survey Engineer **GEODATA**

July 2019 - December 2020

Semmering Basistunnel, Austria

- Tunnel surveying
- 3D Laser scanner measurements

Teaching Assistant

TU Graz

March 2021 - January 2022

Q Graz, Austria

- Integrated navigation
- Sensor fusion
- Indoor navigation

Software Engineer

TU Graz

🛗 Sep 2019 - January 2022

- **Q** Graz. Austria
- Software Architect
- Project management
- Automation
- Data Analysis
- ML forecasting
- Statistics
- Geoinformatics
- Automotive industry
- Automotive Battery and Electric Vehicle Testing

Data Scientist & Data Engineer

niceshops GmbH

🛗 January 2021 - pending

♥ Vienna, Austria

- Finances (all types of tasks)
- Cloud computing
- AI & ML tasks
- · Courses inside the house / teaching (Looker)
- · Research about demand forecasting
- Dynamic pricing
- Looker

STRENGTHS

Hard-working Decision Making

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Motivator & Leader

Conflict Resolution

Time Management

Target oriented

Able to travel

Flexibility and Adaptability

Problem solver

LANGUAGES

Serbian | Croatian | Bosnian **English** German

Russian



HOBBIES



Reading

I am trying to read a book per week.



Sports Addict

At a young age I enjoyed playing tennis, but my interests migrated towards Fitness and healthy food.



Travelling

After living in a rustic, small town for the past 18 years, I was craving change and adventure. Six years later, I've traveled to more places during college than the first two decades of my life.



Trading

I love to analyze the markets and factors that may impact the price on daily/weekly and long term basis.